So you know that
getting a click is
what starts this whole
system off. And if
your thumbnail doesn't match
what your audience expects,
even if your strategy
is great, this isn't
going to work. And
that is why thumbnails
matter a lot. But
the real question is,
how should you make
yours? And the truth
is, you've got a
few different paths. And
the right one depends
on your current skill
level, your time and
your goals. So instead
of giving you one
answer, I'm going to
walk you through options
like a decision matrix.
So let's start with
option one. So option
one is you basically
learn photography and Photoshop.
This is the highest
effort route. And James
and I, we have
made a gigantic thumbnail
photography and Photoshop course.
It's detailed and powerful.
But for most of
you, it is probably
overkill. Unless you want
to become a designer
or you want to
get really good at
Photoshop photography. It's just
not a 10x move
doing it this way.
It will take you
weeks and you won't
be posting until it's
done. So if you
want to go all
in on the craft,
that's great. It's there.
It's there for you.
But if you're just
trying to get a
few clicks, I would
hold off on that
option. So then option
two is use AI
to generate thumbnails. Now,
this is faster. You
can get pro level
looking photography with no
experience at all. But
there are some trade
-offs. So the first
is you are still
going to need to
edit these. And if
you don't have Photoshop
and you're using things
that don't allow you
to edit in kind
of a new detail,
you're going to be
holding yourself back. But
also AI sometimes gives
you weird hands or
extra thumbs, or an
odd face, and it
can make you look
a bit cartoony. And
the thing that sucks
about that is some
audiences hate AI generated
images because it feels
fake. It doesn't feel
authentic. And that's actually
the reason I stopped
using AI because I
wanted to have a
more authentic tone in
my content. So it
can work, but it's
not perfect. And then
option three, use photos
of yourself and you
keep everything super simple.
So this is what
I do now. You
basically bad shoot a
set of photos in
one session. And you.
Change your expression in
each of them like
this and your pose
and your lighting. And
then you have props
and things that might
relate. And then all
you do is you
reuse the same photos
over and over again.
So you can see
here, same face, different
color, t -shirt, same
pose, next one, slightly
zoomed in. And people
don't really spot that
you're using the same
things over and over
again. So that saves
a lot of time.
Now I do then
go to edit these
in Photoshop myself, but
doesn't take long. And
it also means I'm
not reinventing the wheel
every time. And they
are pretty simple. And
then option four. Is
you outsource this. So
if Photoshop overwhelms you
or your designs aren't
getting clicks, you hire
someone to edit them.
Now in the outsourcing
module in the advanced
sections, I'll show you
exactly how to do
that. But if you're
hesitant to spend money
on this, you need
to ask yourself if
it takes me three
hours to make a
thumbnail. Is that a
10 X move? The
answer is no. I'm
telling you now it's
not.
So if you hire
someone out, you can
then spend those three
hours on something that's
actually going to grow
your business. So you
basically just want to
pick one of those
options. And master it.
And one more thing.
Members, when you submit
your thumbnails for feedback,
we're going to be
honest with you. If
it's not strong enough,
we're going to tell
you because it could
waste a huge amount
of your time if
no one clicks on
your videos. And for
those of you who
are new to this
sort of thing, this
is going to be
one of the steepest
learning curves in YouTube.
And we're probably going
to send you back
to remake them over
and over again. But
once you get a
system and you get
the practice in, it's
going to speed up
massively. So don't beat
yourself up or don't
feel like you feel
this is behind. A
lot of people come
into this, realize the
importance of thumbnails and
go, wow, it takes
me just as long
to do the thumbnails.
As the video. But
that is actually an
important part of the
process. We will get
you through it so
long as you don't
quit. OK, so now
don't do anything. Just
go and watch the
next phase. I'm going
to teach you strategy.
And at the end
of that, we're going
to come up with
three or four ideas
and keep pushing you.